-=TLF字幕組=-
翻譯：諾阿諾阿，馴鹿
翻譯：現代孔融讓榴蓮，茶包泰迪
校對：諾阿諾阿
「佩小姐的奇幻城堡」
你是否感到過自己所做的都毫無意義
Do you ever feel like nothing you do matters?
就像在海灘上留下的腳印
You leave footprints on the beach,
第二天便消失不見
and tomorrow they're gone.
就像不斷重複的一天又一天
Like it's just today over again.
人們說十幾歲時
They say your teen years
就是要交朋友、盡情玩耍
are for making friends and having fun...
對我來說這樣更糟
which made me feel even worse.
嗨，艾米，我是傑克
Hey, Amy. It's Jake.
咱倆數學課一起上
I'm in your math class.
嘿，別忘了給自己買成人紙尿褲
Hey, don't forget your adult diapers.
呵呵
Yeah, right.
傑克，有電話找你
Jake. Phone for you.
但那一天開始，一切都變了
But that day, everything changed.
謝謝你送我，雪莉
Thanks for the ride, Shelley.
怎麼讓你去照顧你爺爺呢？
So, how come you have to go deal with your grandpa?
我爸他工作忙，走不開
My dad couldn't get out of work.
他還有工作？
I didn't think he worked.
我還是給爺爺打個電話吧
I'm just gonna call Grandpa.
我是亞伯
Hello, this is Abe.
我是傑克
Hey, it's Jake.
別過來！聽我說
No! Don't come here. Listen to me.
這裏不安全
It's not safe.
千萬別來
Stay away.
爺爺，你今天吃藥了嗎？
Grandpa, did you take your pills today?
放槍的櫥櫃的鑰匙，本來在抽屜裏
The key to my gun cabinet, it was in the drawer.
現在不見了！
And now it's gone.
我爸拿走了，你不記得了？
Yeah, Dad took it, all right?
安全起見，好吧
For safekeeping. It's okay.
你爸拿走了？沒有槍我怎麼對付他們？
Your father wants I should fight them without a gun?
上帝保佑他
God bless him.
他是怎麼了？老年癡呆？
What's his deal, Alzheimer's?
智力衰弱
Dementia.
那傢伙嚇我一跳
That guy gave me the heebie-jeebies.
有什麼事就喊我
Holler if you need me.
爺爺？
Grandpa?
雪莉！
Shelley!
怎麼回事？
What's goin' on?
有人闖進來了
Someone broke in.
我車裏有槍，在這兒等我
I've got a.38 in my car. You wait there.
爺爺！
Grandpa!
911，您遇到了什麼緊急情況？
911. What's your emergency?
我需要醫務人員
911? Yeah, I need the paramedics.
地址是棕櫚環路2040號，我爺爺…
It's at 2040 Palm Circle. My grandpa...
您遇到了什麼緊急情況？
Sir, what's your emergency?
爺爺
Grandpa.
你得趕快走
You have to get away from here.
能聽見我說話嗎，先生？
Sir, can you hear me?
聽我說
Please. Listen.
去島上
Go to the island.
先生，醫務人員正在趕來
Sir, paramedics are on their way.
找到艾默生
Find Emerson.
那張明信片
The postcard.
找到圈
Go to the loop.
1943年9月3號
September 3rd, 1943.
沒事的
It's okay.
不要動，救護車馬上來了
Just don't move. There's an ambulance coming.
你肯定覺得我瘋了
I know you think I'm crazy.
但鳥會跟你解釋的
But the bird will explain everything.
答應我，小老虎，你一定去
Will you do this, Tygrysku? Promise me?
我一定去
I promise, yes.
我以為自己能保護你
I thought I could protect you.
我早就應該告訴你
I should have told you years ago.
爺爺！告訴我什麼？
Grandpa. Tell me what?
爺爺！
Grandpa!
雪莉，小心後面
Shelley, behind you!
那裏沒有人
There was no one there.
聽我說，傑克…
May I say, Jake...
鑒於才過去一個月
that considering this was only a month ago...
我認為你的表現已經很好了
I think you're doing exceptionally well.
你是說不瘋了？
Apart from being crazy?
做惡夢和焦慮並不代表你瘋了
Having nightmares and anxiety doesn't make you crazy.
那看到並不存在的東西呢？
What about seeing things which aren't there?
在某些特殊情況下
Actually, in traumatic situations,
這種現象也很常見
it's not at all uncommon.
你頭腦中的潛意識會提取電影中的畫面，或是…
Your subconscious mind drew an image from a movie or...
是因為一個故事
It was a story.
我小時候，爺爺會給我講故事
My grandpa told me stories when I was a kid...
講他在戰爭中遇到的那些怪物
about monsters that he fought in the war.
你看
So there you go.
他當時傷的很重
He was brutally attacked...
所以你認為傷他的是非人類，是怪物
and in your head, the man who did it was inhuman, a monster.
不過也不是人
It wasn't a man, though.
警察說紗門上
The cops said that dogs
有狗抓過的痕跡
scratched up the screen door...
他追到樹林裏
and he chased them off into the woods.
驗屍官說他當時心臟病發作
And the coroner said he had a heart attack.
警察說
And the cops said...
狗會吃掉屍體軟組織
that dogs go for the soft parts.
他們檢查了叉子上提取到的DNA
They DNA tested the fork...
裏面有動物的DNA
and it had animal DNA.
就這麼結案了
So, that's case closed.
聽你說的，你爺爺應該是個了不起的人
He sounds like an extraordinary gentleman.
你倆很親近嗎？
Were you very close?
波多黎各
Puerto Rico.
這裏
Here.
那裏有個湖，湖水晚上會發光
There's a lake where the water glows in the dark.
還有一個秘密通道
And a secret tunnel.
我藏在裏面躲過了怪物
That's where I hid from the monsters.
我小時候他經常照顧我
He used to babysit me a lot.
跟他在一起的時候，我有種特別的感覺
When I was with him, I felt special.
我的鴨子又干了
My duck was dry again.
亞伯，都11點了，他怎麼還沒睡
Abe. It's, like, 11:00. What is he doing up?
我要當一個探險家
I'm gonna be an explorer.
爺爺在幫我計劃第一次航行
Grandpa's helping me plan my first voyage.
世上的角角落落都已經被探過了
Everything's already been discovered, buddy.
他們恐嚇彼此
They terrorize each other...
然後大肆破壞，毀掉了島上的其他地方
before wreaking havoc on the rest of the island.
別理你爸爸
Pay no attention to your father.
他什麼都不知道
He knows bubkes.
走吧，小老虎，該睡了
Come, Tygrysku. Off to bed.
給我講個故事吧
Can you tell me a story?
經常講的那個？
The usual?
很久很久以前
Okay. Once upon a time...
有一個小男孩
there was a little boy...
要帶圖片
With the pictures.
圖片啊
Pictures.
很久很久以前
Once upon a time...
有個小男孩名叫亞伯
there was a little boy called Abe.
就是你嘛
That was you.
是我
That was me.
他住在一個很美麗的福利院
And he lived in a lovely children's home
就在威爾士附近一座小島上
on a little island near Wales...
那裏每天都陽光燦爛
where the sun shone every day.
那裏的女校長叫佩瑞格林小姐
The headmistress, Miss Peregrine...
她非常非常聰明
was very clever.
她還抽煙斗
And she smoked a pipe.
她還能變成鳥
She could turn into a bird.
那裏是特殊兒童之家
It was a home for special children...
比如布朗溫，還有維克多
like Bronwyn and Victor.
他倆都非常強壯，比得過十個壯漢
They were both as strong as 10 men.
還有休
And Hugh...
休身體住著蜜蜂
Hugh had bees living inside him.
艾瑪呢？
Where's Emma?
她會飄起來
She could float.
她比空氣還輕
She was lighter than air.
必須得穿上鉛做的鞋子
She had to wear special shoes made of lead
否則會飄走
to keep her from floating away.
她現在在哪裏？
Where is she now?
應該還在島上吧
She's still on the island, I believe.
我的爸爸媽媽把我送到那裏
My mama and papa sent me there...
和特殊的小孩子們一起生活
to live with the special children.
小老虎該睡覺了
And now, Tygrysku, time for sleep.
他總是叫我小老虎
He used to call me Tygrysku.
就是波蘭語的小老虎的意思
It's Polish for "little tiger."
一點都不像我
He couldn't have picked a less appropriate nickname.
我那時候膽子很小
I was always a chicken.
你的爸爸媽媽為什麼把你送走
Why did your mom and dad send you away?
我們那時住在波蘭，那裏不安全
Well, where we lived in Poland, it wasn't safe.
那裏有怪物
There were monsters.
哪種怪物？
What kind of monsters?
超級大的怪物，有很長的手臂
Huge ones, with long arms...
沒有眼睛
and no eyes...
觸手就像這樣
and tentacles like this.
可笑的是
The dumb thing was...
好多年，我都相信他的故事
for years, I actually believed his stories.
這個是米勒德，他是隱形人
And this is Millard. He's invisible.
老師說那些照片是專門唬人的
My teacher says they were trick photos.
你相信她說的嗎？
And did you believe her?
爸爸說你大概是在某家
Dad says you probably found them
舊貨商店找到的
at a junk store someplace...
就在你旅行的時候
when you went traveling.
我永遠不會騙你，小老虎
I would never lie to you, Tygrysku.
但是你就是騙我了，福利院，還有怪物
But you did, about the home, the monsters.
爸爸說
Dad told me.
你爸爸知道
Your father knows very well
我小時候住在兒童之家
I went to live in the children's home.
他說那時候波蘭的確有怪物
He said there really were monsters in Poland...
但不是長觸角的那種怪物
just not the kind with tentacles.
他說你被送去威爾士是因為波蘭有壞人
He said you got sent to Wales 'cause there were bad people.
那些人會殺掉所有跟他們不一樣的人
People who wanted to kill anyone who was different.
我不想繼續談這個了
I don't wanna talk about this anymore.
他說那裏的孩子是很特殊
He said the children were special...
但不是你說的那種特殊
but not the way you said.
發現什麼好東西了？
You find something good?
哦，快瞧瞧，真棒
Oh, look at that. That's awesome.
帶走吧
You should take that.
走吧，小伙子
Come on, buddy, let's roll.
你怎麼跟沒事兒人一樣？
How are you so okay?
傑克，你跟爺爺的關係比我跟他親近多了
Jakey, you were a lot closer to him than I ever was.
他是個好爺爺
He was a wonderful grandpa...
但不算是個好爸爸
but not such a great dad.
他所有的工作
Never seemed to pick a job...
都早出晚歸
that didn't involve late nights
還經常出差很久
or long trips away, though.
我和你蘇希姑姑
Me and Aunt Susie always kind of thought
都以為他出軌了
he was, maybe, cheating on our mom.
對不起，我知道你很崇拜爺爺
I'm sorry, buddy. I know how much you worshiped him...
但事實就是這樣
but there it is.
驚喜吧！！
Surprise!
生日快樂，傑克表哥
Happy birthday, Cousin Jake!
傑克，真高興
J-dog, it's great you're coming
你暑假和我們一起過
to spend a summer with us.
等會兒帶你去看新船
Wait till you see the new boat.
很期待呢
Can't wait.
是蘇希姑姑
It's Aunt Susie.
我猜這個禮物你會喜歡
Thought you might wanna open this one.
是爺爺送你的
It's from your grandpa.
我看到的時候已經包好了
Found it while I was packing up.
我猜他是想給你的
I figured he meant to give it to you someday.
謝謝姑姑
Thanks.
致傑克，以及他即將發現的世界
To Jake, and the worlds he has yet to discover.
最最親愛的亞伯
My dearest Abe...
希望你能收到這張卡片
I hope this card finds you well.
孩子們和我都非常想你
The children and I yearn to hear your news.
希望你很快能再來看望我們
I do hope you will visit us again soon.
我們都非常期待見到你
We should so love to see you.
此致
With admiration...
阿爾瑪·佩瑞格林
Alma Peregrine.
呃…兩年前寄來的
H mm. Only two years ago.
很可能她還活著
I suppose it's possible she could still be alive.
對
Right.
我可以見見她
I could meet her.
也許能發現
Maybe even find out what it was
爺爺想讓我知道的事情
Grandpa wanted me to know.
但是如果她死了呢？
But what if she's dead?
格蘭醫生
Dr. Golan...
我們很關心
we are very concerned
傑克現在的心理狀況
with Jake's state of mind right now.
我沒法放下工作
There's no way I'm putting my life on hold
帶你去威爾士啊
to take you to Wales.
爸爸可以帶我去
Dad could take me.
他可以去看鳥…
And he can look at birds...
順便完成他的書
and work on his book.
你也能休息一段時間
It means you get a break.
就像格蘭醫生說的
As Dr. Golan said...
也許我就能放下了
maybe I can move on.
就像一種了結
Like, closure.
有機會去看看這個福利院
Having an opportunity to see this children's home...
將現實和幻想分離開
and separate fantasy from reality...
也許會有用
may be helpful.
至少
And at the very least...
這樣一次旅行能讓傑克有機會
a trip like this provides a chance to...
說再見
say goodbye.
「卡瑞霍姆，人口92人
"Cairnholm. Population of 92.
「因其最接近
"Best known for its proximity...
「奧古斯塔號郵輪最後的安息地而為人所知
"to the final resting place of the cruise liner Augusta...
「奧古斯塔號於1915年沉沒
"which sank in 1915.
「島上只有一家旅館」
"There is just one hotel..."
只能住那兒了
That's us.
希望那裏有波本酒
Yeah. I hope there's bourbon.
傑克！快看
Jake, check it out.
是只游隼
That's a peregrine falcon.
游隼，和那個女校長的名字一樣
A peregrine, like the headmistress?
是啊
Sure.
說不定這就是為什麼爺爺提到
That's probably where Grandpa came up
變成鳥的事情
with that whole turning into a bird thing.
說不定那真的是她
Or maybe, maybe that's really her!
佩小姐！
Hey, Miss Peregrine.
我是傑克
It's me, Jake.
亞伯·波特曼的孫子
I'm Abe Portman's grandson.
拜託別在我們頭上拉便便
Please don't crap on us.
爸，我開玩笑呢！
Oh, my God. Dad, I'm kidding.
這…有人嗎？
What the... Hello?
有人嗎？
Hello?
有人在嗎？
Anybody home?
你好
Oh, hey.
你知道這裏的經理在哪兒嗎？
Any idea where I'd find the manager of this place?
是我，抱歉久等了
That's me. Sorry to keep you.
剛帶奧吉叔去上廁所了
Just helping Uncle Oggie to the loo.
我是凱文，樓上有房間
I'm Kev. There's room upstairs.
太好了
Oh, great.
我很快回來
I'll be back in a bit.
凱文去幫我們準備房間了
Kev's just getting our suite ready.
還要等一會兒
Um, while we're waiting...
要不咱們去海灘看看？
I thought maybe we could go check out the beach.
我還以為咱們要去兒童福利院呢
I thought we would go to the children's home.
那些鳥是在海灘上築巢嗎？
Is the beach where the birds nest?
我們…可以很快看一眼
I thought we could just check it out real quick.
我可以自己去福利院
I could go to the home by myself.
你就不用太匆忙了
Then, you can really take your time and enjoy it.
別這樣，小傑，你媽知道了肯定會抓狂的
Come on, Jakey. You know your mom would freak.
要不找個人帶我去吧
What if we can find someone to take me?
嗨，各位
Hey, dudes.
- 爸！別！
- 別吵
- Dad. Don't.
- Shh! I got this.
你們誰
I was just wondering if any of you guys...
有興趣帶我兒子
might be interested in taking my son here
去島的另一邊嗎？
to the other side of the island.
你倆叫什麼啊？
So, what are your names?
我是蟲子，他是D哥
I'm Worm. This is MC Dirty D.
壞小子D哥
MC Dirty Bizniz.
我還以為你改了？
I thought you changed it.
沒有
No.
你不記得了？
No, you did, remember?
露絲說壞小子D哥
When Ruth said "MC Dirty Bizniz"
聽起來好像你褲子破了似的
made it sound like you cacked your trousers.
對，但她說這個名字聽起來
Yeah, but she said "Dirty D" sounded like
好像個人衛生有問題
a personal hygiene problem.
聽起來像是外號…
Wait. Are these, like, nicknames, or...
是藝名，我倆是威爾士最屌的說唱歌手
Stage names. We're the sickest rappers in Wales.
快，蟲子，給美國佬露兩手
Go on, Worm. Show this Yank how it's done.
現在？
What? Now?
我要把教堂攪個地覆天翻
I like to get wrecked down the Priest Hole
因為你爸去教堂領救濟的錢
Your dad's always here 'cause he's on the dole
我們的韻腳最屌但聽起來好像不難
Our rhymes are tight Yet I make it look easy
我們的節奏最炫好像火爆的咖喱飯
Our beats are hot like chicken jalfrezi
挺好的
Oh, yeah, no. It's good.
咱們抄小道吧，D哥
Should we take the shortcut, D?
這樣快一點，從這兒走
We'll get there quicker. Take it from me.
這裏下去？
What, down here?
去吧
Go.
這邊？
This way?
這…
What the...
這是去福利院的路嗎？
Is this even the way to the children's home?
要穿過那片林子
Right through those trees.
鞋丟了就丟了吧，孩子
No use crying over a lost shoe, boy-o.
那個福利院…發生了什麼事？
The children's home. What happened to it?
德軍空襲，炸彈正好落到福利院屋頂
A German air raid. Bomb fell right on the roof.
1943年9月3號
September the 3rd, 1943.
那…之後那些孩子呢？
Where did they go after?
女校長和孩子們呢？
The headmistress and the children.
無人生還，可憐的小東西們
Not one survivor. Poor little buggers.
都還那麼可愛
And they were lovely, too.
為什麼爺爺不告訴我們他們都死了？
Why didn't he tell us that they all died?
他離家去參軍，三個月後
He leaves to join the army, and 3 months later,
他認識的人都死了
everyone he knows gets killed?
就算是爺爺也沒法把這編成晚安故事啊
Not even Grandpa could turn that into a bedtime story.
也難怪他害怕做爸爸
Well, no wonder he was scared of being a dad...
和別人親近
being close to anyone.
聽我說
Listen.
你應該找人談談這件事
You need to talk about all this with someone, buddy.
我們可以給格蘭醫生打電話
We should call Dr. Golan.
真是個好天氣
Certainly some enjoyment today.
我可以跟
Er, do you mind if I go hang out
其他孩子一起玩嗎？
with those other kids today?
他們叫我一起玩
They asked.
當然了，很棒啊
Yeah? That's awesome.
亞伯？
Abe?
不！
No!
你是艾瑪
You're Emma!
還有雙胞胎
And the twins.
奧利弗
And Olive.
布朗溫
And Bronwyn.
他是米拉德
And he's Millard.
不對啊，你死了
No, you're dead.
你們都死了
All of you, you're all dead.
他雖然能隱形，但是也死了
He's invisible, but he's still dead.
我們都沒死
None of us are dead.
天吶，難道是我死了？
Oh, my God. Am I dead?
不是
No.
剛才在裏面
You called me Abe.
你為什麼叫我亞伯？
In the house. Why?
你跟他很像
You looked like him.
一瞬間很像而已
Just for a moment,
後來你就又喊又叫
before you started screaming...
跑掉了，還撞到了腦袋
running away, and concussing yourself.
這是怎麼回事？
Wait. What's happening?
我們在等天黑
We're waiting until the coast is clear...
然後去圈裏
before we go into the loop.
隔牆有耳，不可不防
You never know who might be watching.
你剛說去哪裏
Wait. Before we go into what?
快走吧，傑克
Please, Jake.
佩小姐在等你，她看見你們的船了
Miss Peregrine's waiting. She saw you on the ferry.
她派我們來接你
She sent us to get you.
嘿！
Hey!
你準備去哪裏啊？
Where do you think you're going?
回房間啊
To my room.
我是這裏的住客
I'm a guest here.
你看這像旅館嗎？
Does this look like a hotel to you?
對啊
Yeah.
我有鑰匙
No. I've got a key.
你問問經理，他知道
Talk to the manager. He'll tell you.
我就是經理
I'm the manager, boy.
他是美國人，可能是軍人
He's American. Maybe he's army?
胡說
Bollocks.
聽他的口音，真難聽
Listen to his accent. It's terrible.
他是個間諜
He's a spy.
什麼？
What?
我不是，我是遊客
No, I'm not. I'm a tourist.
要我說，我們讓他說實話
I say we should get the truth out of him
按老規矩來
the old-fashioned way.
快走！
Come on!
傑克，快上來！
Jake, get on!
快點！
Come on! Get on, boy!
原來你們都是真的！
I can't believe you're real. You're all real!
不是一直在告訴你嘛
We have been trying to tell you.
但是原來我也很特殊
But I'm special, too.
什麼？
What?
剛才在酒館啊，奧利芙看見了
in the pub. Olive, you saw.
那些東西飛來飛去的
Right? Everything was flying and breaking.
是我幹的
And that was me!
用意念
I was doing it with my mind.
是我幹的
No, that was me.
米拉德？
Millard?
對啊
Yeah.
你沒穿衣服？
Are you naked?
對啊
Yeah.
哦
Oh.
我不…
I don't...
1943年一顆炸彈落在你們頭頂
A bomb dropped on you in 1943.
現在就是1943年
It is 1943.
1943年9月3日
September the 3rd, 1943.
每一天，這一天
All day, every day.
就是我們的圈
It's our loop.
分秒不差
Right on time.
我是佩小姐，幸會幸會
Miss Peregrine. Delighted to meet you.
希望酒館老闆不會再
I do hope I'm not going to have the pub landlord
帶著警察找上門來了
knocking on my door with the police again.
這個月已經殺過他們兩次了
I've had to kill them twice this month.
太不方便了
It's been terribly inconvenient.
米拉德打破了幾件東西，再沒了
Millard broke a few things. That's all.
還有奧利芙好像放了點火
And Olive may have started a tiny fire.
但是他們要傷害傑克的
But they were going to hurt Jake.
瞧瞧你
Look at you.
亞伯上一次寄給我的照片上
The last time dear Abe sent me a photograph...
你還是個小寶寶呢
you were just a tiny tot.
別站著了，快進來吧
Don't just stand there. Come in.
茶都要涼了
Your tea's getting cold.
你怎麼知道酒館的事？
How did you know about the pub?
你體重大概109磅，對吧？
You weigh approximately 109 pounds, correct?
我不…
I don't...
你跑掉後6分鐘布朗溫和雙胞胎就回來了
Bronwyn and the twins returned 6 minutes after you ran away.
我可能漏掉了什麼
I think I'm missing something.
你覺得酒館是安全的
And quite apart from the fact
所以最可能的情況就是你
that the perceived safety of the pub...
一路跑回了酒館
makes it the most likely place to which you would flee...
跑回酒館要花18分鐘時間
it would take you 18 minutes to run there.
艾瑪和米拉德坐馬車過去
Emma and Millard would have been moments behind...
會稍晚一點
on the horse and trap,
他們的速度是8.2英里每小時
traveling at 8.2 miles per hour.
考慮到酒館裏發生的混亂
Factoring in some sort of kerfuffle at the pub...
和返程中增加了你的重量
and the return journey with your added weight...
你們會在4點過13分準時到達
you would arrive here at 13 minutes past 4.
好了，你的茶要加糖嗎？
Now, then, do you take sugar?
可以了，謝謝你，奧利芙
That'll do. Thank you, Olive.
茶太燙了可不好
Nobody enjoys over-boiled tea.
我來幫你吧，伊諾克
Let me help you with those, Enoch.
不麻煩了，我可不想攪了你們的雅興
Don't bother. Wouldn't want to interrupt your tea party.
節哀順變，傑克
I'm so sorry for your loss, Jake.
看來你知道了
You know, then.
我知道如果亞伯活著
I know if Abe were alive,
一定會通知我們你要來
he would have told me you were coming.
我們到外面喝茶吧
Shall we take our tea outside?
謝謝
Thank you.
他死之前，讓我找到你
Before he died, he told me to find you.
有些事他想讓我知道
There was something he wanted me to know.
他說你會向我解釋所有事
He said you could explain everything.
確實如此
That's absolutely true.
少有我解釋不了的事情
There are very few things I can't explain.
我們就是通用語中所說的
We're what's known, in common parlance,
「異能」
as "peculiar."
晚了51秒，菲奧娜
51 seconds late, Fiona.
對不起，佩小姐
Sorry, Miss Peregrine.
晚餐需要準備多少胡蘿蔔？
How many carrots do you need for supper?
一顆就夠了
Just one will do.
剛才說到，有些人擁有異能
As I was saying, some people are peculiar.
是家族中遺傳下來的隱性基因
It's a recessive gene carried down through families.
然而，很多家庭的很多代人中
Yet, many generations can pass
都很難出現一個異能的孩子
without a peculiar child being born.
因此，異能人很多年來一直受到迫害
And alas, peculiars have been persecuted through the ages.
所以我能才生活在這樣的地方
Hence, we live in places like this.
威爾士？
In Wales?
只要選對了日子，哪裏都是一樣
Anywhere will do if you pick the right day.
這就可以了，菲奧娜
That's fine now, Fiona.
我的異能是我是只回時鳥
You see, I'm a type of peculiar called an Ymbryne.
也就是說我可以
That means I can...
對，你可以變成鳥
Yeah, you turn into a bird.
話是沒錯
I do. Yes.
不過這沒多大用處
But that's not very useful.
回時鳥的主要能力是可以操控時間
An Ymbryne's main skill is the manipulation of time.
我們挑個安全的日子，安全的地點
We choose a safe place, a safe day...
然後創造圈
and create a loop.
這是什麼意思？
What do you mean?
一個時間圈可以保持24小時
A loop preserves the last 24 hours.
重置時間圈，就可以重新生活這一天
Reset the loop, and the day is yours to live in again.
每天重置
Reset it daily...
就可以永遠停留
and you can stay there forever.
與世隔絕，保證安全
Entirely safe from the outside world.
剛剛好，布朗溫，好姑娘
Right on time, Bronwyn. Good girl.
所以總是由回時鳥
And that's why we Ymbrynes
來照顧孩子們
are charged with the care of the young.
沒有人會老去
And no one ever gets older.
這是最好的方法
It's best for everyone this way.
我向你保證
I assure you.
每一隻回時鳥都會…
Every Ymbryne commits herself...
創造和守護一個這樣的地方
to the creation and upkeep of a place like this.
這是異能孩子的家園
A home for peculiar children.
你已經見過雙胞胎了
You met the twins.
這是克萊爾
This is Claire.
你也見過米拉德了
Millard you met.
那是休
And that's Hugh.
休，不要作弊
Stop cheating, Hugh.
米勒，你又犯規了！
Millard, that's a foul again.
才不是！裁判？
No, it wasn't. Ref?
如果你們玩的時候非要吵架
If you two can't play soccer without squabbling...
那就最好不要玩
I do wish you wouldn't play at all.
你知道裁判是幹什麼的嗎？
Do you know what a referee is?
下午好，我是霍勒斯
Good afternoon. I'm Horace.
很高興見到你
Delighted to meet you.
我們急需新鮮血液的注入
We sorely need some new blood here.
襯衣不錯
Super shirt, by the way.
謝了
Thanks.
你肯定知道艾瑪
You know Emma, of course.
差不多人都認齊了
And I think that's everyone.
布朗溫是不是有個兄弟？
Didn't Bronwyn have a brother?
對，維克多在樓上
Yes. Victor's upstairs.
等等，伊諾克和奧莉芙去哪兒了？
Wait, where did Enoch and Olive go?
鬼知道
Heaven knows.
從我們去找傑克時，伊諾克就不見了
Enoch's been off sulking ever since we went out to get Jake.
佩小姐，有個警察在敲門
Miss Peregrine, there's a policeman at the door.
他說來處理酒館的事
He says it's about the pub!
我們等會再談這事，艾瑪
We'll discuss this later, Emma.
不是他們的錯
It wasn't their fault.
真的，他們只是想要幫我
Honestly, they were just trying to help.
謝謝
Thanks.
你沒我想的那麼傻
You're not as wet as I thought.
她不會殺人的，對吧？
She's not really gonna kill anyone, is she?
只要她能說服那個人
Not if she can talk her way out of it.
幫我個忙吧
Would you help me with something?
通常都是伊諾克干的
Enoch usually does it, but like I said,
不過他現在應該在哪兒生悶氣呢
he's off sulking somewhere.
是因為我嗎？
Is that because of me?
他佔有慾很強
He's possessive.
所以…你要我幫你什麼？
So, what did you need help with?
我的一項日常工作
One of my daily chores.
把松鼠寶寶送回樹上
Put the baby squirrel back in the tree.
什麼松鼠寶寶？
What baby squirrel?
每天都會發生？
That happens every day?
分秒不差
Like clockwork.
能幫我把繩子拴在腰上嗎？
Now, would you mind tying that rope around my waist?
一定要抓緊繩子啊
Right. Promise to hold on tight.
差點搞砸了
I nearly messed that up.
亞伯也是…第一次的時候
Abe did, too, the first time.
這以前是他的工作
This used to be his job.
艾瑪，我得告訴你件事
Emma, I need to tell you something.
他死了
He's dead.
我知道
I know.
佩小姐猜到了，她總是對的
Miss Peregrine guessed, and she's always right.
沒事的
It's okay.
我很久以前就和他說過再見了
I said goodbye to him a long time ago.
你們很親近是嗎？
Were you close?
我以為是
I thought we were.
一度
For a while.
但我覺得應該不是
But I suppose not.
容我問一句，他喜歡你，對吧？
Can I ask, was he like you?
他很像你，傑克
He was like you, Jake.
我要去換件衣服，準備吃晚餐了
I need to go and change for supper.
你會和我們一起用餐嗎？
Will you be dining with us?
我不能在外面待太晚
I can't stay out late.
晚餐五點半開始
Supper's at 5:30.
那…挺早的
Uh... That is pretty early.
幸好我們不都是八歲的孩子
The fact we're not all eight years old
給佩小姐減少了不少負擔
seems to have eluded Miss Peregrine.
你可以借件亞伯的衣服穿
You can borrow some of Abe's clothes.
他的房間在閣樓
His room's in the attic.
傑克
Jake!
來認識認識伊諾克
Come and meet Enoch properly.
你應該不太適應這裏的環境
You must feel pretty out of place.
不用擔心
Don't worry.
我習慣了
I'm used to it.
我不擔心
No. I wasn't worried.
但還是給你一些忠告，開誠佈公的講
Some advice for you though, man to man.
如果你只是因為喜歡艾瑪才待在這裏
If you're thinking of staying just because you like Emma...
就不必了
don't bother.
她心碎以後
You see, she swore off romance decades ago...
已經多年不沾情愛了
when she got her heart broken.
她也不會改變想法的
And she's never gonna change her mind. So...
伊諾克，我不是…
Enoch, I wasn't...
你在幹什麼？
What are you doing?
是不是很棒？
Isn't he amazing?
你剛才做的是什麼？
What did you do?
這個？
This?
傑克，這還不是最有趣的
Jake, this isn't even the fun part.
你想看最有趣的嗎？
Do you want to see the fun part?
它們就像傀儡
They're like puppets.
聽我的命令
Just do anything I tell them.
如果是人的話就更有趣了
It's even more fun with people.
你該看看我以前參與的
You should have seen some of
史詩級的戰爭
the epic battles they used to have...
發生在我父母的葬禮上
at my parents' funeral parlor.
你還需要領結
You'll need a necktie.
我祖父在旅行期間，做了什麼？
So what did my grandpa do when he was traveling?
參觀其他的時間圈
Visited other loops.
是嗎？做什麼？
Really? To do what?
傑克，有些問題
Jake, there's some questions
我不能回答你的，好嗎？
that I can't answer, all right?
所以你最好還是
So, it would be a lot easier for me if you just...
不要問了
stopped asking them.
你在幹什麼？
Hey! What are you doing?
米拉德
Millard.
去穿件衣服
Go and put some clothes on.
懂禮貌的人不會吃晚餐的時候不穿衣服
Polite persons do not take their supper in the nude.
好吧！
All right. All right.
傑克你可以坐這裏
You can sit here, Jake.
瞧瞧伊諾克
Look at Enoch.
他又嫉妒了
He's jealous.
我嫉妒什麼？
Why would I be jealous?
你們想結婚就結好了，與我無關
Olive can go marry Jake, for all I care.
伊諾克，別這樣，她沒這樣想
Don't be mean, Enoch. She doesn't want to.
她只是因為有訪客而激動罷了
She's just excited to have a visitor.
沒人要結婚
Nobody is marrying anybody.
現在大家快吃飯，別等菜涼了
Now, eat up your food before it gets cold.
休
Hugh!
你的網罩呢？
Where's your net?
休，別這樣！
Hugh! You have to stop doing this, Hugh.
傑克，你一定覺得十分詭異吧
Must be very strange for you, Jake.
見到了你祖父的朋友
Meeting your grandfather's friends.
來到另一個世紀
Visiting another century.
你生活的時代有宇宙飛船嗎？
Are there spaceships in your time, Jake?
像飛俠哥頓裏的一樣
Like the Flash Gordon books.
好了！奧莉芙
Now, now, Olive.
我以前說過什麼
What did I say about asking questions?
我們不討論將來
We don't discuss the future here.
只活在當下，享受一切
We enjoy living in the good old here and now.
克萊爾，你怎麼不吃?
Claire, why aren't you eating?
在傑克面前，她不太好意思
She's embarrassed in front of Jake.
沒關係的
Don't be. Please.
傑克，你的異能是什麼？
So, Jake, what's your peculiarity?
我…我沒有異能
Oh, I'm not peculiar.
看到了吧
And that, my friends,
這就是他為什麼不能和我們待在一起
is why he will not be staying with us...
不管我們怎麼勸他
no matter how hard we try to persuade him.
我們已經說過這件事了，傑克只是來做客的
We've spoken about this. Jake is just visiting.
他也許想留下呢
He might want to stay.
你想待在這裏嗎，傑克？
Don't you want to stay, Jake?
今晚還是…
Tonight? Or...
永遠，你應該永遠留在這裏
Forever. You should stay forever.
沒必要的話為什麼要留下來？
Why would he, if he doesn't have to?
他可以在外面生活，慢慢變老
He can live out there, grow older...
享受時光
have a good time instead.
然後像他祖父那樣，離開人世
He'll leave, just like his grandfather did.
艾瑪！
Emma!
抱歉
Excuse me.
她去哪裏？
Where's she going?
伊諾克，這樣很不好！
That wasn't nice, Enoch.
你明明知道亞伯離開我們
You know perfectly well why Abe left us.
是為了去參軍
To join the army.
接著他遇到了一個姑娘，然後結了婚
And then he met a lady, and had a nice wedding cake...
還有個可愛的小寶寶
and a lovely little baby.
孩子們！
Children.
我知道你們都想認識新朋友
I know you'd all like a new friend...
但傑克在佛羅里達還有很多自己的事
but I'm sure Jake has plenty of his own back in Florida.
我希望在我接完電話後
I think you should all get ready
你們可以準備好去看電影了
for movie time while I answer that.
可是你總是讓我們待在那裏
But you always let us stay for it.
嗨，我是亞伯
Hello, this is Abe.
大家都還好嗎？
How is everyone?
傑克，你的我多加了棉花糖糖
Yours has extra marshmallows, Jake.
米拉德，把睡衣穿上
Millard, put some pajamas on.
這裏好熱
It's too hot in here.
不要抱怨了
Stop moaning.
抱歉
Excuse me.
我祖父給我講過
My grandpa told me about this.
霍勒斯能把他做的夢投放出來，是嗎？
Horace projects his dreams, right?
他過去常聽收音機
He used to listen to the radio.
極其乏味，我已經倒背如流了
Gets tedious when you know every word off by heart.
很好，這件我要了
Splendid. I'll take it.
很多都是關於服裝的
He dreams about clothes mostly.
很高興見到你
Delighted to meet you.
襯衫不錯
Super shirt, by the way.
他什麼時候夢到這個的？
When did he dream this?
昨晚
Last night.
有些夢有預見性
Some of his dreams are prophetic.
但絕大多數還是關於服裝的
But, mostly they're about clothes.
預見性是說，他能預見未來？
Prophetic as in, he can see into the future?
回時鳥，她是誰？
An Ymbryne. Who is she?
佩小姐，你認識她嗎？
Miss Peregrine, do you know her?
傻瓜
Don't be silly.
霍勒斯只是做了個噩夢而已
Horace must have just had a bad dream. That's all.
足夠了，謝謝你，霍勒斯
That's quite enough of that. Thank you, Horace.
我想我該走了
I should probably get going.
你可以在這待一晚上，你願意的話
You could stay the night, if you wanted to.
這樣就不要晚上走回去了
Rather than walk home alone in the dark.
這座島不是挺安全的嗎？
But the island is very safe, isn't it?
當然
Of course!
我是說這裏的路特別難走
I only meant the path is dreadfully bumpy.
傑克可能會跌倒
Jake could trip.
或許你可以帶他走近路？
Perhaps you could show him the shortcuts.
這樣他就不會跌倒了
Should he ever need to avoid bumps.
不留下來看看如何開始新的一天嗎？
Won't you at least stay to see the reset, Jake?
超震撼的
It's really quite spectacular.
留下來吧，傑克！
Yeah! Stay, Jake!
什麼聲音？
What was that?
我的手機
It was my phone.
可能是在時間圈裏，一直都沒信號
It's been dead the whole time in the loop. I guess now...
你的手機？
Your phone?
對，就像電話
Yeah. Like a telephone.
可以打電話
You can call people...
可以發短信
send written messages.
對了，你會喜歡這個的
Wait, you'll love this.
你可以拍照
You can take a picture.
按那裏…那…對
Press that, there. Yeah.
看見了沒？
See?
怎麼了？
What's wrong?
想到有一天你會長大
It's just funny to think that one day, you'll grow up.
就像亞伯
Like Abe did.
結婚生子
Get married, have children.
孫子孫女
Grandchildren.
你也許還會給他們看這張照片
You might even show them this photograph.
而我還在這裏
And I'll still be here.
你能離開這裏嗎？
Couldn't you leave some day?
如果你想的話，能生活在現實世界嗎？
And live in the present, if you wanted to?
不行
No.
在那裏待幾分鐘
More than a few minutes in your time
時間就會趕上來
and the years would catch up.
你會變老？
You would age?
這個好像是霍勒斯夢中的回時鳥
I think it's the Ymbryne from Horace's dream.
你確定它不是一隻普通的鳥嗎？
Are you sure it's not just a bird?
我不知道，它難道不會變身嗎？
I don't know, wouldn't it change?
不能，她受傷了
She can't. Not if she's hurt.
我要把她帶進去，你該走了
I need to take her inside. You should go.
請不要說話了
Please don't say anything else.
我討厭說再見
I hate goodbyes.
我明天再來
I'll come back tomorrow.
不用著急，我永遠都在這裏
There's no hurry. I'll be here forever.
嘿！
Hey!
我在這個破島上轉了一整天了
I've been all over this damn island.
你去哪兒了？
Where the hell were you?
我正好往回走
Um, I was just on my way back.
對不起，我忘了看時間了
I'm sorry. I lost track of time.
我和蟲子，還有D哥玩兒了一天
I was having a blast with Worm and Dirty D.
D哥？
Dirty D?
你知道嗎？
You know what?
我覺得這樣挺好，很健康
This is good. This is healthy.
你認識了古怪的朋友
You're making weird friends...
跟其他年輕人們一樣
and doing teenage stuff.
我覺得這挺好的
I think this is normal.
格蘭醫生肯定會同意這麼做的
I'm sure Doctor Golan will approve.
嘿，那個美國佬
Hey, you. American!
到這兒來
Get over here.
哦，他們倆在那兒
Oh, look. There they are.
D哥和蟲子
There's D-Bag and Worm Man.
是你幹的嗎？
Did you do this?
什麼？不是！
What? No.
當然不是
Of course not.
肯定不是我們
It wasn't us.
這位先生，我不知道這裏發生了什麼
Listen, sir. I don't know what happened here.
但是我兒子一直和他朋友在一起
But my son and his friends have been together all day.
傑克肯定不會幹這種事兒的
Jake would never do anything like this.
胡說！我們今天就沒見過他！
Bollocks! We haven't seen him!
你昨天付了我們錢
You paid us yesterday.
我們今天為什麼要免費陪他玩兒？
Why would we hang out with him today for free?
傑克，你今天有沒有和他們在一起？
Jake? Were you with them or not?
沒有！對不起！
No. I'm sorry.
你不是真的覺得這是我做的吧？
But you don't seriously think I could do this?
我想我們已經都弄清楚了
I think we're done here, sir.
能幫我留個言嗎？
Can you pass on a message for me?
你就告訴格蘭醫生
Can you tell Doctor Golan...
要不是她慫恿進行這次荒謬的旅行
that if she hadn't encouraged this cockamamie trip...
我兒子也不會
maybe my son wouldn't be
跑到一個廢棄的房子裏面呆了一整天
moping around all day in a derelict house...
以至於都神情恍惚了！
having a goddamn breakdown!
喂？
Hello?
爸，我沒有
Dad, I'm not.
我沒事兒
I'm fine.
你不好
No. You're not.
你有事兒，傑克
You're not fine, Jake.
到這兒來就是個徹頭徹尾的錯誤
Coming here was a terrible, terrible idea.
對不起，我說謊了
Look, I'm sorry I lied. I just wanted...
鬧鐘定在早上8點
Just set your alarm for 8:00 a.m.
我想早點兒去海灘上看看
I wanna get to the beach early.
剩下這幾天
The rest of the time we're stuck
在這個破島上
on this craphole island...
我們倆必須一起行動
we're sticking together.
你去哪兒？
Where are you going?
去樓下喝一杯
Downstairs for a drink.
親愛的佩小姐
Dear Miss Peregrine...
我不想讓你們擔心
I don't wish to alarm you...
但是我的一個線人告訴我
but one of my informants sent me this.
巴倫先生的一些同夥
It would appear that some of Mr. Barron's group...
出現在英格蘭黑譚鎮附近
are in Blackpool, England.
如果我沒記錯
If I recall...
艾娃塞小姐在那兒有一個時間圈
Miss Avocet has a loop there.
請給她發出預警
Please warn her and suggest...
讓她盡快建立一個新的時空循環
that she make a new one right away...
隱匿好行蹤
well-hidden.
請珍重
And take the greatest care yourself.
祝好，亞伯
With love, Abe.
2016年1月
January, 2016.
準備好去海灘了嗎？
Who's ready to hit the beach?
我去…
Oh, my...
難以置信！
Unbelievable.
在鳥巢區域架設備？
Right in the middle of a nesting area?
哪兒來的外行居然這麼幹？
What kind of idiot does that?
事實上，主要築巢區在那邊
Actually, the main nesting area is over there.
你想看看嗎，我可以領你過去
I can show you if you'd like.
很高興能在此遇到一個同樣喜歡拍攝鳥類的人
It's marvelous to meet a fellow bird spotter.
約翰·拉蒙特
John Lamont.
富蘭克林·波特曼，這是我兒子，傑克
Franklin Portman. This is my son, Jake.
約翰·拉蒙特
John Lamont.
你居然帶著這麼棒的相機來這兒
That's a hell of a camera you got there.
謝謝，這地方真是太讚了
Oh, thanks. It's absolutely fantastic.
我是來給我的書拍一些插圖的
I'm here to do some snaps for a book I'm writing.
你們二位是過來度假的嗎？
So, you gentlemen here on holiday?
不幸的是，她的翅膀
Unfortunately, her wings were flapping
呼噠的就像一隻鳥！
as much as the bird's!
我覺得你們
I think you fellas are
現在想的是另一種鳥
thinking of another kind of bird.
你今天不再去海灘照相了嗎？
So, you're not going to the beach today?
有什麼意義呢？
What's the point?
如果那個傢伙舉著相機
If that guy is gonna cover Cairnholm
把整個島的照片都發表在他那個包裝精美的書裏
in some big, glossy book...
誰還會看我拍的照片
no one's gonna even wanna look at mine.
我去睡個午覺
Might just have a nice afternoon nap.
你倆今早在哪裏
I don't suppose you saw Uncle Oggie
看見老歐吉了嗎？
on your travels this morning, did you?
按說他現在應該過來了
He's usually here by now.
我可以幫忙去找找他
I could go look for him.
你哪兒也別想去
You're not going anywhere.
傑克，你回來了！快來和我們一起玩兒！
Jake, you're back! Come and play!
我想要先見見佩小姐
I need to see Miss Peregrine first.
你知道她在哪兒嗎？
Do you know where she is?
傑克，你回來了，太好了！
Jake. You're back. How wonderful!
它怎麼樣了？
How's it doing?
艾瑪說這是一隻回時鳥
Emma said it was an Ymbryne.
她，不是「它」
"She." Not "it."
回時鳥都是女性
Ymbrynes are always female.
艾瑪說的非常正確
And Emma was quite correct.
這位是艾娃塞小姐
This is Miss Avocet.
她的時間圈在英格蘭黑譚鎮
Her loop's in Blackpool. England.
這是私人信件，傑克
That was a private letter, Jake.
誰是巴倫先生？
Who is Mr. Barron?
佩小姐，如果我爺爺
Miss Peregrine, if my Grandpa
和什麼危險的人物有瓜葛
was involved with dangerous people...
我有必要將這些都告訴給警察
I need to tell the police.
告訴警察？
Police?
你這是在暗示亞伯是非正常死亡嗎？
Are you implying Abe died an unnatural death?
我在樹林裏找到他時
I found him in the woods...
他的眼睛不見了
with his eyes missing.
我覺得這很不正常
I'd say that was pretty unnatural.
除非必要，我不想討論這些讓人不愉快的事兒
Unless essential, I don't discuss unpleasant matters.
回時鳥的職責是保護孩子，傑克
An Ymbryne's duty is to protect children, Jake.
我不是小孩兒了
I'm not a child.
爺爺他想讓你把這些都告訴我
He wanted you to tell me everything!
哦，真鬱悶啊
Oh. How frustrating for you.
鑒於佩小姐的規定
Between Miss Peregrine's rules...
以及我那條不想嚇壞你的室友守則
and my housemates' little pact not to scare you off...
所以，沒有人會給你答案的
it's like no one's telling you anything!
要不你來告訴我？
Why don't you, then?
反正你也不想我留在這兒
It's not like you want me here.
伊諾克，你不能告訴他，你保證過不說的
Enoch, you can't. You promised.
奧利芙說得對
Olive's right.
但是我知道有一個人
I do know someone who can get away
可以不用遵守這項規定
with breaking rules though.
你想去見見他嗎？
Want to meet him?
伊諾克，別這麼做，求你了！
Enoch, don't do this. Please!
是你想大家一起玩的
You want to spend time with me and Jake,
我們可以一起玩
we can all play together.
自己說的話不記得了？
That's what you said.
就是這兒了
Here we all are.
讓開，奧利芙
Move, Olive.
你要是非這麼做
If you're going to be like that,
我以後就不跟你做朋友了
then I don't want to be your friend.
伊諾克！別打擾維克多，布朗溫會不高興的
Enoch, leave Victor alone. It really upsets Bronwyn.
別鬧了，菲奧娜
Stop fussing, Fiona.
你不覺得傑克應該和這裏的每個人都認識一下嗎？
Don't you think Jake should meet everybody?
他想把你嚇跑，傑克
He's trying to frighten you away, Jake.
他一直都嫉妒艾伯，現在他又開始嫉妒你
He was always jealous of Abe. And now he's jealous of you.
還是過來跟我們一起玩兒吧
Come and play with us instead.
我想我應該去見見維克多
I'd quite like to meet Victor.
你先請
After you.
你好維克多
Hello, Victor.
我是傑克，不好意思打擾你
I'm Jake. I'm sorry to disturb...
他聽不見你說話
Yeah, he can't hear you.
你好傑克，我叫維克多
Hello, Jake. I'm Victor.
你想知道是什麼殺害了我嗎？
Do you want to know what killed me?
你在這兒呢，他沒和你一起嗎？
There you are. Is Enoch with you?
到了每天散步的時間了
It's time for our daily walk.
艾瑪，是誰害了維克多？
Emma, who killed Victor?
是那些白色眼睛的人嗎？
Was it the people with the white eyes?
我跟你說了別問這麼多
I asked you not to ask questions.
我爺爺去世的那晚我見過一個
I saw one the night my grandpa died.
這樣的人
A man.
如果你的確見過這麼一個
If it really was one,
你應該告訴佩小姐
you have to tell Miss Peregrine.
你能從照片裏認出這個人嗎？
Could you recognize him from a photograph?
你有照片嗎？
Do you have one?
那就跟我走，跟我去個地兒
Come on. There's somewhere I go to be alone.
我在那兒存了些東西
I have things there.
是這兒嗎？
Is this the place?
不是，這只是我們去哪兒的途徑
No. This is how we get there.
艾瑪！你的鞋！
Oh! Emma! Your shoes!
鉛鞋！
Lead shoes!
歡迎來到我的秘密基地
Welcome to my secret hideout.
你是，你是怎麼？
How did you...
空氣
Air.
這是我的能力
It's my peculiarity.
它可以幫我實現想法
It does what I want.
傑克
Jake...
你爺爺退隱前
before your grandfather retired...
讓我保管這些
he asked me to keep this safe.
這些是我爺爺的舊地圖
This is my grandpa's old map.
上面標記了時間圈的所在地
It shows you where the loops are.
就是他
That's him!
這就是我見過的那個人
That's the man I saw.
他是誰？這就是巴倫
Who is he? That's Barron.
他是領頭人
He's the leader.
什麼的領頭人？
The leader of what?
這些人都是誰？
Who are these people?
壞人，壞的異能者
Bad people. Bad peculiars.
亞伯終其一生都在追捕這些人
Abe dedicated his life to hunting them down.
這些是他沒有找到的
These are the ones he never found.
「追捕」是什麼意思？
What do you mean, hunting?
他們會襲擊時間圈
They raided loops.
殘忍的殺害其中所有的孩子
Whole homes full of children left for dead.
亞伯只是以暴制暴
Abe took lives to save lives.
你出生後，為了保護你他就退隱了
He only retired when you were born to protect you.
保護我什麼？
From what?
如果我告訴你全部
If I tell you the rest,
你要保證你不逃避
you have to promise not to run away.
傑克，你是屬於這裏的
Jake, you belong here.
你知道我不屬於
You know I don't.
我和你不一樣
I'm not like you.
我是個普通人
I'm just ordinary.
不，你不是
No, you're not.
傑克
Jake...
只有異能人才能進入時間圈
only a peculiar can enter a time loop.
不是，這不可能
No. That can't be right.
我是說，我要是異能人我應該知道
I would know.
好吧
Fine.
那麼我就給你看看其他的
Then I'll show you something else.
快來！會趕不上的
Hurry. You'll miss it.
回時鳥通常會選擇一個完美的日子去建立時間圈
Ymbrynes usually pick the perfect day to create a loop.
但是佩小姐是匆忙間選擇的日子
But Miss Peregrine had to make this one in a rush.
為什麼？
Why?
因為德國人會用炸彈摧毀我們的房子
Because the Germans were about to drop a bomb on the house.
問題是
The point is...
1943年9月3日不是個完美的日子
September the 3rd, 1943 wasn't perfect.
那個殺害了維克多的傢伙那天又回來了
The thing that killed Victor came back.
等等，小心！
Wait! Watch out!
你會讓她分心的！
You'll put her off!
你能看見，是不是？
You can see it, can't you?
沒有人能看得見
No one else can.
他們是隱形的，傑克
It's invisible, Jake.
這就是亞伯的天賦
That was Abe's greatest gift of all.
他可以看見那些怪物
He could see the monsters.
我們管他們叫靈體變異人
We call them Hollowgast.
簡稱靈人
Hollows for short.
我爺爺跟我提過有變成怪物的人
My grandpa told me about people who turn into monsters.
就是他們嗎？
Is that what they are?
我會詳細跟你解釋的，傑克
I will explain everything, Jake.
考慮到現在的情況，我恐怕沒得選
I fear it's my duty now, considering.
但是你要知道
But you should know that in doing so,
我這麼做的確破壞了我曾經發過的誓
I'm breaking a solemn promise.
你一出生我就知道你是異能人
I knew you were peculiar when you were born.
但是你爺爺讓我什麼都不要告訴你
But your grandfather forbid me to tell you anything.
他最大的願望就是希望你能有一個正常的童年
His dearest wish was for you to have an ordinary childhood.
我的童年的確過得很平凡
I definitely had that.
他本來打算等你18歲之後再告訴你的
He intended to tell you the truth when you turned 18.
他希望那些睡前故事可以提前鋪墊一下
He hoped his bedtime stories would pave the way.
這是我的書
Here's my book.
很多年前
Many years ago...
從我們的族群中分裂出了一批人
a splinter faction emerged among our people.
對於異能人只能存在於時間圈中非常不滿意
Disaffected peculiars tired of living in loops.
這就是巴倫先生
That's Mr. Barron.
他認為按照他的方法
He believed that by harnessing the essence
提取回時鳥的能力
of an Ymbryne's powers...
他和他的同夥可以獲得永生
he and his cronies could gain immortality...
而且不用困在時間圈裏
and be able to live outside loops.
於是他就設計了一個試驗
He devised an experiment.
他綁架了一隻回時鳥
He kidnapped an Ymbryne...
在不顧那只回時鳥死活的情況下
not knowing or caring
開始了試驗
whether she would survive the experiment.
但是巴倫和他的同夥
But the fate of Barron and his group
下場相當慘烈
was more horrifying still.
為什麼巴倫沒什麼變？
Why didn't Barron turn into one?
他變了
He did.
可在這之後幾年裏
But years later...
他發現了可以逆轉異常
he found a way to reverse the effects.
變回人類的方法
To regain humanity.
他們變的不老不死，但是以靈人的形式存在
They had become not immortal gods, but Hollows.
危險冷血致命的
Invisible beasts, dangerous...
隱形怪物！
cold-blooded, deadly.
記得我之前提過他們襲擊時間圈嗎？
Remember I told you they raided loops?
這就是原因
This is why.
巴倫發現食用其他異能人
Barron discovered that by consuming
特別是兒童期的
the eyes of other peculiars...
異能人的眼睛
especially children...
可以令他恢復
he began to change.
食用到足夠多的眼睛，靈人就能
Consume enough, and a Hollow
完全變回人形
can fully regain its human form.
祝各位好胃口
Bon appetit.
只有巴倫和他的同夥能夠復原
Just as Barron and some of his friends did.
其他還是以靈人的形態存在
The rest of them are stuck as Hollows.
你是說巴倫吃了我爺爺的
Are you saying that Barron ate my grand...
他自己已經不需要吃眼睛來維持形態了
He needs no more eyes himself.
恐怕是他指使靈人找到了你爺爺，吃了他的眼睛
But I fear he led a Hollow to your grandfather. Yes.
在他們第一次襲擊了時間圈後
After the first attacks on loops...
我們也開始更加注意隱蔽，建立新的時間圈
we all got better at hiding, making new loops,
隱匿我們的行蹤
keeping our whereabouts secret.
而那些靈人變得越來越貪婪
The Hollows grow more desperate every year...
巴倫則希望能壯大自己的隊伍
and Barron wishes to help his friends.
佩小姐！快來！艾娃塞小姐醒了
Miss Peregrine, come quickly. Miss Avocet's awake.
突然，我又飛了進去
And suddenly, I flew into it again...
什麼都看不見
Bang! Bang! I couldn't see anything.
佩小姐！他們發現了我新建的時間圈
Oh, Miss Peregrine. They found my new loop.
孩子們，我想盡一切辦法試圖救下她們
The children. I tried to save them...
但是靈人實在是太多了
but there were so many Hollows.
我都不記得我是怎麼逃出來的
I don't know how I escaped.
你現在安全了
You're safe now.
我們不可能安全的
None of us are safe.
他們在我的時間圈裏面安了裝置
They set up the machine in my loop.
裝置就在黑潭塔的地下室
They put it in the cellars at Blackpool Tower.
那些人還在那兒
They're still there.
裝置？試驗用的
Their machine? The experiment.
他們打算再做一次試驗！
They intend to do it again.
這次他將使用更多的回時鳥
This time, he's using more Ymbrynes.
他還是想獲得永生
He still wants to be immortal.
Do Hollows only attack peculiars?
當然不是！
Of course not.
他們就是野獸，傑克
They're monsters, Jake.
他們會將眼前的一切都屠殺殆盡
They'll slaughter anything in their path.
島上有些羊群被殺了
Some sheep on the island were killed.
他們不會已經到了這裏吧？
You don't think they're here already, do you?
你有看到長著白色眼睛的人嗎？
Have you seen anyone with white eyes?
孩子們，很抱歉，我們不能繼續住在這兒了
I'm sorry, children. We can't remain here.
什麼？
What?
我們乘坐明早第一班渡船離開這裏
We'll leave on the first ferry off the island tomorrow.
回去收拾行李
Pack anything of importance.
我去做些三明治然後哄你們上床睡覺
Then it's sandwiches and early to bed.
離開就再也不會來了嗎？
Are we leaving for good?
我們什麼時候再回來？不會再回來了
When are we coming back? Never.
如果佩小姐明天晚上
If Miss Peregrine's not here
不重置時間圈
to reset the loop tomorrow night...
這房子就徹底被炸毀了
the house gets bombed.
什麼？我們的房子？
But our house.
別哭
Don't cry.
佩小姐會給你們
Miss Peregrine will find you
重新找一座漂亮房子的
another lovely house, somewhere else.
一旦這個時間圈關閉
Once this loop closes, that's it.
我就再也不能回到自己的時空了
I can't get back to my own time.
你在那裏過得也不是很開心啊
You didn't seem very happy there.
我不能就這麼走了！我還有家人
I can't just leave! I have a family!
你一直覺得自己平凡
And you felt ordinary.
覺得自己什麼都不能改變
Like, nothing you do changes anything!
現在你有一個機會
Now you have a chance to do something
可以拯救世界
that changes everything!
傑克，我們現在有危險
Jake, we're in danger.
而你是我們中唯一一個可以看見靈人的
And you're the only one who can see the Hollows.
是，我確實可以看見他們，但是我不是我爺爺
Yeah, see them, sure. But I'm not my grandpa!
我不是，我不知道怎麼去戰鬥
I'm not, and I can't fight.
我不會殺人
I can't kill somebody.
只有一個理由可以讓我留下來
There's only one reason that I'd stay here...
別說了！
Please.
你走吧
Just go.
傑克，傑克原來你在這兒！
Jake? Jakey, there you are.
謝天謝地！
Thank God!
聽他們說找到了一具屍體時嚇死我了
When I heard they found a body, I freaked.
這兒也有流浪狗嗎？
Are there stray dogs around here?
你說什麼？
What you talking about?
我是說
It's like...
流浪狗發現受傷的動物後
when they find an injured animal,
會先吃掉其中的軟組織
they go for the soft parts first.
我父親去世的時候也是這樣
Same thing happened to my father.
警察已經快到了
The police are on their way.
爸爸，我得走了
Look, Dad. I've gotta go.
不行，你那兒也不能去，傑克
What? No. You don't, Jake.
如果這不是意外
If this wasn't an accident,
那就是這個島上有個瘋子
there's a lunatic on the island.
我認識這個島上的每一個人
I've known everyone on this island my whole life.
除了你和他
Except you, and him.
而他在酒吧裏坐了一下午
And he's been in the pub all afternoon.
我也是，我一直都在睡覺
So have I. I was sleeping.
那個盲人呢？
What about the blind fellow?
我以為他也是個盲人
I assumed he was blind.
一個戴墨鏡的先生
Gentleman with the dark glasses...
是和我同一天坐渡輪一起過來的
arrived on the same ferry as me?
我總能看見他在這附近
I kept seeing him around.
傑克！
Jake!
傑克，等等！
Jake! Wait!
你兒子還好吧？
Is your son all right?
不好
No.
他有心理障礙
He has mental health issues.
我追不上
I can't go.
我幫你追，我經常會來個5公里跑
Let me. I run 5-Ks all the time.
你好！
Hello?
你好？
是你嗎，年輕人？
Is that you, young man?
你能進入？
You came through...
你是個異能人？
You're peculiar?
是的
Oh, yes.
真是多虧了你
And I'm extremely grateful to you.
這些日子想要找到時間圈越來越難了
Terribly hard to find loops these days.
你故意從海灘那兒一直尾隨我？
So, you followed me from the beach on purpose?
不不不
Oh, no.
我在很早以前就已經開始關注你了！
I've been following you much further than that.
格蘭醫生？
Doctor Golan?
有時候
Sometimes.
合適的時候
When it suits me.
一般來說能夠局限我異能變化的
The breadth of my peculiarity...
只有我的想像力
is purely limited by my imagination.
只有一樣我沒有辦法改變
The only thing I can't change...
就是我的眼睛
is my eyes.
我是巴倫先生，你好嗎？
Mr. Barron. How do you do?
我在你爺爺家見過你
I saw you at your grandfather's.
我本打算從他那兒
I was hoping to get
得到佩小姐的地址
Miss Peregrine's address from him.
但是和我一起過來的旅伴
But, alas, my traveling companion
先我一步找到了他
got to him before I did.
如你所知
As you know...
沒什麼能阻止飢餓的靈人捕食
there's just no stopping a hungry Hollowgast!
說到我那個同伴
Speaking of my traveling companion...
他已經在來的路上了
he's coming.
勸你還是相信我說的
Believe me when I say to you...
當他到這兒之後
you don't want to be here...
你絕對不會想留下來了
when he arrives.
我們繼續往前走吧
So, let's be on our way.
請吧
Shall we?
借過
Excuse me.
等等我
Wait for me.
日曆必須要拿上
I mustn't forget our calendar.
能幫我去客廳拿一下嗎
Could you fetch it from the parlor
艾娃塞小姐？
please, Miss Avocet?
去幫助其他人吧
Go and help the others.
佩小姐
Miss Peregrine, what a pleasure
終於有機會見到你了！
to meet you at last!
我們能進來嗎？
May we come in?
孩子們
Children!
你們都下來吧
Would you make your way down the stairs, please?
巴倫先生！這座房子裏輪不到你來下命令
I give the orders in this house, Mr. Barron.
今天不行
Not today.
傑克已經完成他的任務
You should know that Jake has served his purpose.
如果你們還想保他的命，我建議
If you value his life, I suggest
聽我的！
everyone does as they're told.
- 孩子們！
- 噓！
Children! Shush!
沒人可以命令他們
No one tells my children what to do!
孩子們
Children...
都下樓到這裏來吧
come down here, please.
佩小姐
Miss Peregrine...
我說過讓你安靜！
I thought I told you to be quiet.
孩子們
Children...
為了傑克的安全
for Jake's safety...
我們現在要按巴倫先生說的做
we're going to do what Mr. Barron asks.
他希望我
He wishes to take me with him
跟他一起去黑池
to his rendezvous in Blackpool.
為了保護自己
So, for his protection...
他希望我變成鳥的樣子
he'd like me to assume bird form,
最好是在籠子裏
preferably caged.
他還想把你們也全部鎖起來
He'd like you to make your way into a lockable room,
比如客廳
such as the parlor...
如果令他感到
as he won't release Jake if he fears
有一絲的不安全
an attack could be mounted upon him...
他都不會放傑克走
once he loses his leverage.
是這樣麼，巴倫先生？
Correct, Mr. Barron?
你準備犧牲自己和我們
You're sacrificing yourself and all of us...
僅僅為了救傑克？
for Jake?
巴倫先生帶著一隻空靈，伊諾克
Mr. Barron travels with a Hollow, Enoch.
它一旦來這裏，我們都得死
Once it arrives here, we're all dead.
伊諾克，只有傑克能看到空靈們
Enoch. Only Jake can see them.
他是我們唯一的希望
She means he's our only hope.
能照顧你們
It's been my privilege...
是我的榮幸
to care for you all.
再見！孩子們
Goodbye, my children.
你現在可以放開他了
Now let him go.
傑克，答應我
Promise me one thing, Jake.
你會盡力照顧他們所有人
That you will try to look after them all.
我答應你
I promise.
天要黑了
It's getting dark.
到時候連它們的影子都看不到了
You won't even be able to see their shadows.
我們必須待在房子裏
We have to stay inside.
這樣我們或許還有一絲生機
It's the only place we stand a chance.
他說的對，佩小姐平時
He's quite right. Now, where does
都把武器放在哪裏？
Miss Peregrine keep her weapon?
這邊，跟我來
In there. Let's go.
孩子們
Now, all right, children.
去把每一扇門窗
Make sure all the doors are locked,
都關好，鎖好
and the windows are latched.
全都牢牢關好，快去
Everything must be sealed up tight. Now quickly.
快去！
Quickly! Go!
這兒
Here.
傑克，最好你去接
Jake, I think tonight, you better answer that.
好
Okay.
喂？
Hello?
你好，我是亞伯
Hello, this is Abe.
你是哪位？
Who's that?
你…你不認識我，我是傑克
You don't know me yet. I'm Jake.
哦，你是新來的，歡迎來到這個大家庭，傑克
Ah, you're new. Welcome to the family, Jake.
我不能講太久
Now, I can't talk long...
幫我告訴佩小姐
so just tell Miss Peregrine...
我在空軍基地，我一切都好
I'm at the air base, and I'm fine.
我想告訴你，我很想你
I just wanted to say that I miss you...
如果我讓你失望了
and if I disappointed you...
對不起
I'm sorry.
還有，你是世界上最好的爺爺
You're the best grandpa in the world.
菲奧娜！
Fiona. Got it.
艾維賽小姐！
Miss Avocet.
孩子們
Now, children.
有幾條命令大家要記住
Now that you're all here, there's a few rules.
你們一定要保證自己的安全
Your primary job is to stay safe.
空靈留著我來對付
Leave the Hollow to me.
千萬不要逞英雄
I don't want to see any heroics.
拿著農具的孩子，要記住
Now those of you with garden tools...
你們…
I must insist that you...
不，伊諾克！回來！
No, Enoch. Get back!
快跑！去閣樓
Go. Get to the attic!
接著她！
Take her.
走！走！
Go. Get out!
奧利芙，快走！
Olive, come on!
糟了！要到重置時間了
Crap! It's almost reset!
菲奧娜，你能讓那棵樹長過來麼？
Fiona, is there anything you can do with that tree?
小心點！
Be careful.
我們從這邊窗戶出去
We're going through the windows.
快走，快一點！
Let's go! Quickly!
過來！
Come on!
克萊爾！快下來
Claire, come on down.
小心點
Be careful.
菲奧娜，快走！
Go, Fiona!
快跑！
Let's go!
- 怎麼回事？
- 時間圈關閉了
- Was that...
- The loop closing.
全都沒了
It's gone.
對不起，傑克
I'm sorry, Jake.
我們現在怎麼辦？
What do we do now?
有沒有巴倫和佩小姐的蹤跡？
Is there any sign of Barron and Miss Peregrine?
他們走了，巴倫一定是乘船走了
Gone. Barron must have had a boat.
我們必須去找他們
We have to go after them.
至少我們知道他們要去黑池
We know he's taking her to Blackpool.
黑池離這兒那麼遠
But Blackpool is miles away.
況且下一班船要再等好幾個小時
The next ferry doesn't go for hours.
我們來不及了
We'll never make it in time.
除非我們現在就有條船！
Not unless we go by boat, too.
在黑池這裏有一個時間圈
So, there's a loop here in Blackpool.
只有六個月，是2016年1月11號
It's only six months old. January 11th, 2016.
但現在艾維賽小姐不在了，這個時間圈就無法維持
With Miss Avocet gone, it can't be reset.
時間圈會關閉麼？
Won't the loop close?
它就會回到現實時間
Then it's back to real time.
傑克，你知道這意味什麼麼？
Jake, you know what this means, don't you?
你會死
You're gonna die.
我不是這個意思
That's not what I mean.
我們需要回到自己的時間裏
We have to get to our own time,
但你不用
but you don't.
你可以繼續生活在2016年
You can continue to live in 2016.
為什麼？
But why would I do that?
如果我們殺死巴倫
If we kill Barron...
他死了，時間會繼續向前
he'll be gone, but time will carry on.
他就不會去佛羅里達
He won't go to Florida...
亞伯不會死，你也可以回家了
Abe won't die, and you can go home.
我能看到爺爺了
I could see my grandpa.
我可以向他們解釋發生的所有事情！
Listen, I can explain everything to them.
我可以讓他們再帶我回到島上
I can persuade them to take me to the island and...
你們還會在那裏麼？
Wait, will you still be there?
我們的舊時間圈永遠結束了
Our old loop's gone for good.
我們不會再見的
We wouldn't see each other again.
我以為你想讓我留下來
I thought you wanted me to stay.
我知道你更想見到亞伯
I know you'll choose Abe.
如果我真想你留下，就不會告訴你這些了
If I minded, I wouldn't have told you
找到艾維賽小姐的
So, have you found Miss Avocet's
時間圈了麼？
loop on the map yet?
在這裏，是新建的
It's here. But it's new.
是今年初剛建立的
She made it early this year. That's my year.
如果我們不能在時間圈關閉前出來
If we don't get out before it closes,
我們都要被困在2016年1月了
we're stuck in January 2016.
很好！
Great.
我們全都被時間困住
Time catches up with all of us,
都會死，除了你！有什麼計劃麼？
we all die, except you. Plan?
時間圈在4:30關閉
The loop closes at 4:30.
我們需要抓緊進入時間圈
That means we need to get in,
救出回時鳥，然後盡快出來
rescue the Ymbrynes and then get out.
前提是我們還活著
Yeah, if we're not already dead.
艾維賽小姐說過機器
Miss Avocet said the machine is in the cellar
在黑池塔的地窖裏
of the Blackpool Tower building.
也就是說我們要跟空靈面對面
That means we will be indoors... with Hollows.
不…不需要！我有一個計劃
No, we won't. I've got a plan.
但我需要你們的幫助
But I'm gonna need your help.
不會是這裏吧？
This can't be it, can it?
任何地方都可能是時間圈入口？
Loop entrances can be anywhere.
在倫敦的入口是一個地鐵隧道
The one in London's in a subway tunnel.
你確定是這個？
Are you sure this is it?
我覺得是
I think so.
米拉德，我現在需要你…
Millard, there's something I need you to do first.
我知道
All right. I know.
看！那就是黑池塔，不遠
Look. There's the tower. It's not far.
說得簡單！我可凍死了
Easy for you to say. I'm freezing.
準備好了麼？
Ready?
所有通往地窖的通道都被封了
All of the doors to the cellar are locked.
唯一能找到回時鳥的路就是那裏
The only way to reach the Ymbrynes is through there.
就是通過那個後台
It's backstage.
你能看到多少個空靈
How many Hollows can you see?
4個，算是個好消息
Four. That's good news.
咱倆對好消息的
I think you and I have
定義可不同
very different definition of good news.
這也就意味著巴倫的其他朋友還沒到…
It means Barron's other friends haven't arrived yet.
他們還沒開始做實驗
So they haven't started the experiment.
所以我們還不晚
We're not too late.
艾瑪
Okay, Emma.
你好了麼？你知道要說什麼
You ready? You know what to say.
傑克
Here, Jake.
其他兄弟馬上就會來加入我們
Our brethren should be joining us momentarily.
今天是個…
This is a day to...
下面的聽著
You down there!
巴倫先生，我們殺了你的空靈兄弟
We killed your Hollow friend, Mr. Barron.
現在我們來救佩小姐了
And now we've come for Miss Peregrine.
五分鐘內帶著佩瑞格林小姐
Bring her and all the other Ymbrynes
和其他的回時鳥去碼頭
to the end of the pier in five minutes...
不然有你好看的
or face the consequences.
這些孩子們一定是
These children must be
像他們的校長一樣瘋了
as insane as their headmistress.
空靈們可是很喜歡飽餐一頓呢
Still, the Hollows will be glad of a feed.
你們在哪兒呢？
Where are you?
我知道你們在這兒
I know you're in here somewhere!
聽著
Good. Listen to me.
我要你們跟著阿徹先生和克拉克先生
I want you to follow Mr. Archer and Mr. Clark.
他們會帶你們去碼頭
They're going to take you down to the pier...
吃個下午茶
for a little afternoon tea.
阿徹先生，克拉克先生
Mr. Archer, Mr. Clark...
請帶著空靈們去碼頭吧
gather the Hollows and take them to the pier.
這幾個孩子殺了馬爾薩斯？
Those children killed Malthus?
自從馬爾薩斯殺了亞伯·波特曼
Barron's had it in for Malthus
巴倫先生就想幹掉他
ever since he killed Abe Portman.
我跟蹤了他好幾個月
I tracked Abe Portman for months.
我當時只需要幾分鐘
All I needed was a few minutes...
來問出佩小姐的時間圈地址
to get the location of Miss Peregrine's loop from him.
但是不行
But no!
馬爾薩斯等不及
Malthus couldn't wait.
所以呢
Instead...
我就必須得在那
I had to masquerade as a psychiatrist...
待上三個星期
for three weeks...
偽裝成心理醫生
in Florida!
你去過佛羅里達麼？
Have you ever been to Florida?
我不是讓你們帶著空靈們去碼頭？
Did I not tell you to gather the Hollows?
萬一是個陷阱怎麼辦
What if it's a trap?
愛德華小姐，肯定是個陷阱咯，但那又怎樣？
Of course, it is, Miss Edwards. But what of it?
幾個小屁孩對空靈就是自尋死路
A couple of children against four Hollows.
趕緊行動啊
Let's get this over with.
傑克，我被電線卡住了
Jake, I'm stuck!
快！
Hurry up!
小心
Watch out!
他們來了！
They're coming!
快走
Let's go.
就現在伊諾克！
Enoch. Now!
動手！
Go! Now!
可以看見了
Starting to see them now.
第二步
Phase two.
艾瑪！快！
Emma, go.
別傻站在這兒！去抓住他們！
Don't just stand there. Get them!
幹得好，孩子們，可以開始第二步計劃了
All right. Good job, guys. It's time for step two.
救出佩瑞格林小姐
Save Miss Peregrine!
呃…那算是第三步
That's sort of step three.
在這之前我們得先把巴倫解決了
First, we've got to deal with Barron.
他們現在該回來了
They should've been back by now.
我就說是個陷阱
I said it was a trap.
如果真是這樣
If that's true...
我們要轉移回時鳥了
perhaps we should move the Ymbrynes now.
你認真的麼？
You're not serious?
我看起來像開玩笑的麼？
Do I not look serious?
是誰跋山涉水
Do I not look like a man who has searched the globe...
就為了多吃一個眼睛
looking for just one more eye to eat...
多點兒人性
in hopes of regaining sufficient humanity...
好繼續他的研究？
to return to his research?
是誰不遺餘力花費數年
A man who's spent years hunting Ymbrynes...
抓起這些回時鳥就為了今晚？
in preparation for this night...
整整兩…不…三天都待在威爾士
and two, no, three days, in Wales...
裝作在觀鳥
pretending to look at birds!
我告訴你
I assure you...
我不會傻傻站在這裏
I will not stand idly by...
眼看著一切脫離我的計劃
to see my destiny derailed.
休，就現在！
Hugh, do it now!
回來！
Come back here!
給我抓住他們！
Get them!
下去！
Go. Get down!
你以為你能阻止我？
You think you can stand in my way?
傑克，如果你沒有這點兒異能
You, Jake, content to age and die...
你是不是就滿足於生老病死的生活？
as if you had not the gift of peculiarity at all?
我更高級
I am a higher being.
我知道永生的方法
I hold the secret to eternal life!
抱歉，打擾一下
Sorry to interrupt.
什麼…
What the...
布朗溫
Bronwyn.
傑克，你又沒打中
You missed me again, Jake.
我猜射的准肯定不是你的異能吧
I take it accuracy is not your peculiarity.
亞伯比你強多了
Abe was a much worthier adversary.
別讓他接近回時鳥！
Don't let him get to the birds.
你可得跟我介紹一下你的裁縫
You must put me in contact with your tailor.
回時鳥…回時鳥…我來啦！
Ymbrynes, Ymbrynes! Here I come!
冰凍
Cold?
直到血液都凝固
Wait till the blood freezes in your veins.
你就打算這麼救你朋友？
That was your attempt to rescue your friend, was it?
傑克！
Jake.
我盡量拖住他
I'll hold him off as long as I can.
你什麼時候才能明白
When are you going to realize
自己準頭有多差？
you are a terrible shot with that thing.
帶上其他人，我們在時間圈入口那裏見
Get the others. I'll meet you at the loop entrance.
我這就救你出來
Let's get you out.
反正最後
Eventually...
你也會沒氣可吹
you're going to run out of breath.
窒息而死
And it'll all be over!
為你親愛的傑克和佩小姐…
Death for your beloved Jake and Miss Peregrine...
還有為了我的永生而死
everlasting life for me!
你該吃點薄荷了
And a mint for you.
奧麗芙！
Olive.
對不起，奧麗芙
I'm so sorry, Olive.
這麼多年我都沒珍惜你
All these years, I never appreciated you.
我一直不知道自己有多幸運
I didn't see how lucky I was.
我習慣了你一直陪在我身邊，從沒意識到
I got so used to having you there, I never realized...
沒意識到什麼？
You never realized what?
找到你們的孩子們，創造新的時間圈
Find your children. Create new loops.
傑克
So, Jake...
原來是繼承了你祖父的異能
I see you've inherited your grandfather's peculiarity.
就是像他一樣討厭
You're just as annoying as he was.
說到亞伯
Speaking of Abe...
記得你死後要是看見他
if you should see him in the afterlife...
替我問候他
give him my regards.
不能再讓他帶走你了
Please. We can't risk him taking you again.
伊諾克！其他人呢？
Enoch! Where are the others?
他們都很安全，奧麗芙正帶他們回船上
They're safe. Olive is leading them back to the Ghost Train.
傑克需要我們，巴倫太強了
Jake needs us. Barron's too strong.
你現在沒了佩小姐
You've lost Miss Peregrine.
你什麼都沒了！結束了！
You've lost everything. It's over.
傑克？
Jake?
艾瑪？
Emma?
等一下，那不是我，那是巴倫
No, wait. Look. That's not me. It's Barron.
別聽他的
Don't listen to him.
他才是巴倫，我是傑克
He's Barron. No, I'm Jake.
他是巴倫
That's Barron.
我比傑克准的多
I've got a better shot than Jake.
你倆最好都給我別動
So, neither of you move until we sort this.
聽著，我是傑克
Listen to me. I'm Jake.
我家在佛羅里達，夢想成為探險家
I grew up in Florida and I wanted to be an explorer.
我認為一切都不會改變，因為我很普通
I thought nothing would ever change because I was ordinary.
他是傑克，那是巴倫
That's Jake. Get Barron.
等一下！他是我心理醫生
No. Look. I told him all of this.
這些都是我告訴他的
She was my psychiatrist.
你們來對付他，我去找佩小姐
Look, you deal with him. I'll go find Miss Peregrine.
等一下
Wait.
我可以證明自己
Look, I can prove that I'm me...
因為我並不普通
because I'm not ordinary.
我能做的事情別人不行
I can do something no one else can
我能看到那怪物
I can see the monsters.
看看，是我！
No, wait. It's me!
伊諾克！
Enoch!
我們得走了，時間圈要關了
We need to go. The loop is closing.
我們要走了
Those of us who are leaving.
艾瑪…
Emma.
你愛你祖父
You love your grandfather.
其他的就不用多說了
There's nothing more to explain.
不，我答應了佩小姐照顧你們
No, I promised Miss Peregrine I'd look after you all.
現在她受傷了，你們也不在時間圈裏
And with her injured, and you without a loop...
她會康復的
She'll recover.
到那之前，我們繼續生活在1943年
Until then, we'll be in 1943.
只是像普通人一樣
We'll only age one day at a time.
經歷時間而已
Like normal people.
這也不是什麼壞事
Which can be no bad thing.
那空靈怎麼辦？
What about the Hollows?
只要他們還在，你們就不安全
As long as they're out there, you're not safe.
傑克，沒有你我們也能安全
We don't need you to make us feel safe, Jake.
因為你已經教給我們更好的
Because you made us feel brave.
你讓我們勇敢
And that's even better.
夥伴們，走吧！
Come on, guys. Let's go.
小老虎
Tygrysku.
之後我們就道別了
And then we said goodbye...
時間圈關閉了
and the loop closed.
我害怕你不在這兒了
I was so scared that you wouldn't be here.
我就再也見不到你了
That I'd never see you again.
我很好
I'm safe.
我要送你生日禮物
Let me give you your birthday present.
爺爺，我的生日還有好幾個月呢
Grandpa, my birthday isn't for months.
這是你的路費
For your travels.
傑克，去找她吧
Go to her, Jake.
你有地圖
You have the map.
你能回到1943年
You can get back to 1943.
但他們在船上
No. Even so, they took a boat.
我不知道他們現在在哪兒
I don't know where they are.
但你知道他們曾經在哪兒
But you know where they were.
你是不知道我怎麼過來的
You have no idea how long it took me to get here.
最近的時間圈在加利福尼亞沙漠
The closest loop was in the California desert.
我從那裏去了東京的時間圈
I used it to get to the Tokyo loop.
然後又去了離這兒最近的1942年時間圈
And that led me to the nearest loop back in 1942...
我參加了海軍還受傷了
where I wound up joining the Navy.
這就別多問了
Don't ask.
之後我在倫敦待了兩個月想要…
Then I spent two months in London trying to...
準備好，加速前進！
Ready for full speed ahead!